Day after day, I awake in a daze,
mezamete ha kurikaesu nemui asa ha
目覚めては繰り返す　眠い朝は
And fasten my collar tightly.
eri no tai wo kitsuku shime
襟のタイをきつく締め
As I walk through the door to my classroom,
kyoushitsu no doa kuguru to hon no sukoshi
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し
I have the slightest bit of pride.
mune wo hatte arukidaseru
胸を張って歩き出せる
Then a wind rushed through that normal, everyday life.
sonna nichijou ni fukinukeru kaze
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
I have a feeling I can hear it,
kikoeta ki ga shita
聞こえた気がした
I have a feeling I can sense it,
kanjita ki ga shitanda
感じた気がしたんだ
Beginning to tremble within my chest.
furuedasu ima kono mune de
震え出す今この胸で
I have a feeling it's on its way,
mou kuru ki ga shita
もう来る気がした
As the millions of stars began to disappear,
ikuoku no hoshi ga kiesatteku no wo
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
I sent them on their way,
miokutta
見送った
Waving my hand,
te wo futta
手を振った
Whispering, "Congratulations".
yokatta ne, to
よかったね、と
では、僕らも始めましょう
Well then, we should get started, as well.
Anti-Tenshi Operation HQ
Hey, wait! Since when were you part of "us"?
こらこら待て
お前は何時から俺たちの仲間になった
Ha! What sort of question is that?
ふん　今更何を
I'm here to stand in for the uselessness that is you.
無能のお前らの代わりにだ
忘れたか　クズ
Disappear pitifully, just like toilet paper!
トイレットペーパーのように惨めに消えろ
何だと
What did you say?!
あのな　お前ら
Quit it, you two.
奏が頑張ってくれてんだぞ
Kanade's working hard outside.
この隙に　全戦線のメンバーに会って回るぞ
We need to get in touch with everyone in the Battlefront now.
何だ
What? What's wrong, everyone?
どうしたお前ら
アタシたちはもう
I guess we're satisfied.
いいって言うかね
Hearing your story, it just made sense.
あんたの話を聞いて納得しちゃったんだよ
踏ん切りが付いたって言うかさ
It helped us decide.
We're a group of people like that.
そういうグループだよ
We kind of already knew it without you having to tell us.
言われなくても分かってたんだけどね
After all, our vocalists are gone.
まあ　ボーカル居なくなっちゃったし
岩沢さんとユイの代わりはもう居ないんだよ
There are no replacements for Iwasawa-san and Yui.
ふんッ　しっかし酷いボーカルだったな
Then again, she was a horrible vocalist.
毎日が文化祭みたいで　楽しかったな
Every day was like a culture festival. It was so much fun.
でも　アタシたち以外では大変だったぜ
Although, this is going to be difficult for people who aren't like us.
I bet.
だろうな
If you're going to start this, then finish it.
Otherwise, it'll seem like you tricked us into this.
やるんなら　やりきってくれ
でないと　アタシたち
アンタに説得されただけみたいになるじゃん
If this long-lasting Battlefront's going to be disbanded,
もしずっと続いて来たこの戦線がなくなっちまうんだったらさ
then this world has fulfilled its role, you included.
この世界はアンタも含めてその意味を果たした事になってさ
Knowing that, I can believe this was for the best.
いいふうになったなって思えるからさ
ただ一時アタシたちは
We'll just say that for a time we enjoyed the days of youth we'd missed, and that'll be enough for us.
ありはしなかった青春さ
ただ楽しんでたって事になれば
それだけで十分だなって
何言ってんだよ
Don't be ridiculous. I don't know how it'll end.
分かんねぇよ
Yeah, of course not.
だよな
But well, I've quit worrying.
まっ、あとのことは知らない
アタシたちはもう行く
We'll get going now. Just wanted to say that.
それだけ
じゃあな　新人
See you later,
Newbie!
次もバンドやるよ
We'll be a band next time, too!
Yeah. I'm sure I'll enjoy it all over again.
ああ　きっとまた好きになる
Yeah. Bye now.
うん　じゃあな
Thank you for your hard work in sending off the minions.
下々共の見送り
お疲れ様です
You've got the worst sort of personality, you know?
お前ぜってぇ性格破綻してるからな
破綻などしてない
I do not! You would dare say that to God?!
神に向かってなんてこと言うんだキサマ
Stop being idiots and let's go.
バカやってないで　行くぞ
There are so many of them...
何だこの数は
What's going on?
どうなってんだよ
Where did all the NPCs go?
エヌ·ピー·シーは
It seems these are all that's left.
もうこの辺じゃ、こいつらしか居ないんじゃ
俺たちのやろうとしてること
Maybe they know what we're trying to do?
分かってんじゃないだろうな
ふん　ゲスが
Scum.
Noda?
野田？
Nice going, Noda!
流石だぜ　野田
俺たちのために戦ってくれるのか
Does this mean you'll fight with us?!
バカなことを言うな
Dream on!
I only move when it helps Yurippe!
俺が動くのはゆりっぺの助けになるときだけだ！
へえ、なるっ
I see.
お前もとことん一途なやつだな
You're such a stoic guy.
大山！
Ooyama!
何の取柄もない僕だけど
I don't have any special traits, but I thought even God would be surprised at this!
ここで活躍できたら
神様もびっくり仰天かなって！
Yeah, show Him what you've got!
ああ、見返してやれ！
Don't go forgettin' me.
俺も忘れてもらっちゃ困るぜ
I don't think anyone'd notice even if you disappeared right now!
このままいなくなっても
誰も気づかなそうだからなぁ！
最後にッ
I'll be the one-
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on!
Knockin' on heaven's door.
That's Bob Dylan.
それ、ボボ·ディランだぜ
But very appropriate.
だが、今まさに相応しい
What's it mean?
なんて意味だ
No clue!
さあ
The main characters are coming together.
こいつは役者が揃ってきたな
何だこの世界は
What is this world? Just what is going on here?
何が起きたって言うんだ
More like, what happened to you?
っていうか　お前に何が起きたんだよ
Who're you?
誰だお前
Well, I was in the mountains for a while, but there wasn't enough food to eat.
うん　しばらく山篭りしてたんだが
食いもんが少なくてな
Is that you... Matsushita Fifth?
お前、松下五段かよ
Tasty candy!
You've lost so much weight.
激痩せしたな
体は大丈夫か
Is everything all right?
おお、むしろきれがいい
Yeah! In fact, I feel better than ever.
I feel like I might be able to take on a hundred people now.
もしかしたら、今なら百人組手でもいけるかも知れねぇぜ
それ空手じゃねぇか
That's actually something you do in karate.
まあ、何にせよ助かるぜ
In any case, it's a great help.
何せ、これだけの手勢だ
We've got all of them to worry about.
Let's all get outta this world safely.
無事に去っていこうぜ
メンバー全員でよ
Yeah.
ああ
Goodbye, wild heaven.
よしッ！
Okay.
突破するぞ！
We're going to break through!
ギルドって
The Guild is a great place to hide, but... it's enemy territory, you know?
そりゃあ潜伏するには絶好な場所だけど
Passage to the Guild B2
敵地よ
It's our hideout.
アタシたちの根城よ
そりゃあいるわよね
Of course they'd be here.
ウジャウジャと
Feels like party time.
Damn! This is endless.
くそ、切りがない
First Bridge
音無さん、下を見てください
Otonashi-san, please look below us.
There's more and more of them.
どんどん増えていきやがる
Behind you!
後ろ！
百人だ
One hundred.
何が？
One hundred what?
百人…戦力が増えたと思え
One hundred... consider that the strength of my support.
え？
You don't get it?
分からないのか
お前の意志は引き継げる
I will carry out your will.
Go!
行けッ！
Shiina...
椎名
ああ　あとは任したぞ
Right, I'll leave this to you.
付いて来い　日向
Come with me, Hinata!
You got it!
おお
Where are you going, Otonashi-san?
どこに行くんですか　音無さん
Passage to the Guild B7
More of them are coming out, so does that mean I'm heading the right way?
数が増えてるってことは
この地点合ってるかしら
I don't have much left.
少ない
I can't get through that many with a handgun, either.
あんな数、ハンドガンなんかじゃ乗り切れないぞ
What should I do...?
どうする
ゆりっぺ
Yurippe.
Cha!
チャー
Everyone at the Guild heard the story.
話はギルドの底まで伝わってきた
今は全員が地上を目指している
They're all heading to the surface.
そう
I see.
これを持って行け
Take this.
ありがとう
Thanks!
戦いが…終わるのか…
So the war's... going to end...
Yes, it will.
ええ、終わるわ
I see.
そうか
なら俺たちも解散だ
Then we're disbanding, too.
お前たちが戦うからこそ
We worked hard because you guys fought.
頑張ってこれたんだからな
今までありがとう
Thanks for the support.
Without you, none of it would have been possible.
アナタが居なければ
何も始まっていなかったわ
いや、一人のバカが居ただけだ
No, I'm not that great.
じゃあな
See ya.
Time to go.
行こう
School Cafeteria Interior
行き過ぎたか
I must have come too far.
Old Guild
A moment's respite, I suppose.
束の間の休息ね
天使
I wonder if Tenshi...
ううん、奏ちゃんも頑張ってるかな
I mean, I wonder if Kanade-chan's fighting, too.
I wish I could have understood this world sooner.
もっと早く気づいてあげていられれば良かったかな
もしかしたら　仲良くやっていられたかもれない
If I had, maybe I could have been friends with her.
I mean, we're both girls.
女の子同士なんだから
こんな世界だけど
This world isn't really made for it, but maybe I could have had the chance to co-ordinate some cute clothes with her.
似合う服とか探してあげたりとかできたかも知れない
But... I guess that wasn't possible.
でも　結局は無理か
I can't forgive God, after all.
アタシは神様を許せない
So...
だから
Damn it!
クッソ
Disappear!
消えろ
消えろ…
Disappear! Disappear! Disappear! Disappear! Disappear!
So you see, this equation equals this.
ええ、ですので
Wait, wasn't I just thinking about something...?
あれ
この公式重要なので…
何かを考えていたような
なんだっけ
I'm going to erase this now, okay?
消すぞ、いいか？
えッ？
どうした、中村？
What's wrong, Nakamura?
いいのか？
Can I erase it or not?
あっはい、どうぞ
Yes, please, go ahead.
ああっクッソー
Damn it!
恥じかいた
That was embarrassing.
Hey, Yuri.
ねえってば　ゆり
何やってたのよ　授業中に
What were you doing in the middle of class like that?
何って別に
Nothing special.
単に考え事よ
I was just thinking about something.
"Thinking"? So much that you stopped listening in class?
考え事？
授業が上の空になるような？
もしかして恋？
Could it be love?!
It is, isn't it?
恋ね？
カバ、出来るもんならしてみたいわよ
That's stupid. It'd be great if it was, but it's just not.
I think Fujiwara-kun is interested in you, though.
藤原くんならゆりに脈ありだと思うけどな
って、聞いてるの　ゆり
Hey, are you listening to me, Yuri?
ほら、藤原くん今一人でいるよ
Look, Fujiwara-kun is alone right now.
藤原くん！
Fujiwara-ku-
こら、このッ
Hey, stop that-
って
Wait, who are you?
アンタ誰だっけ
うん？ひとみじゃん
Huh? It's me, Hitomi.
あ、ああ、ひとみか
A-Ah, right. Hitomi.
そうよ、どっか変になっちゃった？
Hey now, is something wrong with you?
そうかも
Maybe.
ふんふん、それはねぇ
That's because...
恋煩いとか言うんでしょう
You're about to say it's because of my heartache, right?
Right!
正解
Get back to your seat.
席に戻りな
Okay!
うん
っと言うわけで
Remember this part.
ここをよく覚えておけ
うん？中村！
Nakamura, where are you looking?
どこ見てるんだ
おい、ゆり
Hey, Yuri.
えっ？
じゃあ中村
Okay then, Nakamura, start reading from the beginning of the next page.
そのまま次のページの頭から読んでみろ
うん？どうした？
What's wrong?
すごく幸せですね
This is a very happy life.
What are you talking about?
何を言っとるんだ
すごく幸せな風景
This is a very happy situation.
アタシには眩しすぎる
It's too dazzling for someone like me.
This is the kind of life everyone lives...
みんなこんな時間に生きてるんだ
いいですね
So wonderful, isn't it? I'm envious.
羨ましいです
ここから消えたら
If I disappear from this place... can I redo my life?
やり直せますかね
こんな当たり前の幸せをアタシは
Will I be able to accept this ordinary happiness?
受け入れられますかね
Nakamura...
中村
ゆり
Yuri?
Losing all my memories...
記憶も失って
性格も変わって
My personality would change...
ならできますよね
I could accept it then, right?
でも、だったら生まれ変わるって何
But then, what does it mean to be reborn?
それはもうアタシの人生じゃない
It wouldn't be my life any more.
別の誰かの人生よ
It would be someone else's life.
人生はアタシにとってたった一度のもの
There's only one life for me.
And it's right here.
それはここに
たった一つしかない
There's only one.
This is my life.
これがアタシの人生
I can't give it to anyone else.
誰にも託せない
奪えもできない人生
I can't get another, either.
押し付けることも
I can't force it upon another, forget about it, erase it,
trample it, laugh about it, or overdramatise it.
忘れることも
消すことも
踏み躙ることも
笑い飛ばすことも
美化することも
I can't do anything to it!
何もできない
We have no choice but to accept the one and only life we're given, no matter how cruel and heartless it may be.
ありのままの残酷で、無比な
たった一度の人生を受け入れるしかないんですよ
先生、分かりますか
Do you understand what I mean, Sensei?
That's why I fight.
だからアタシは戦うんです
That's why I continue to fight!
戦い続けるんです
だって、そんな人生
Because I...
一生受け入れられないから
I can never accept another life!
手を伸ばせ
Give me your hand!
ふんふん
Hey, there! Looks like we made it in time.
よッ
間に合ったようだな
音無くんと日向くん？
Otonashi-kun and Hinata-kun?
I'm here too, by the way.
僕も居るんだが
戻ってこれた
I made it back?
Kanade heard you, or rather, said she felt an explosion of your presence, and brought us here.
お前の声がッ
いや、お前の思いが爆発してるって
奏でがここまで連れてきて
Kanade-chan?
奏ちゃん？
うん
そう
I see. Looks like I owe you all one.
みんなのお陰ね
助けられちゃった
You guys saved me.
でも、アンタたちどうしてここにいるの
But, why are you all here?
We left the surface to the others.
任せてきた
俺たちの思いは
They said they would carry out our will.
みんなが引き継いでくれたんだ
それで、アタシを助けに来たの
And so you came to save me?
We came to fight beside you.
一緒に戦いに来たんだよ
同じじゃない
Same difference.
I guess. But you make us worry.
まあ、そうだけど
ゆりっぺは心配だからな
Why don't you fix yourself up first?
とりあえず、服を整えたら？
うん？
さあ、行くわよ！
Okay, let's head out!
あ、ああ
S-Sure.
ったく
Man, she never changes.
相変わらずのペースだな
Passage to the Guild B20
Hey, doesn't it look like they're protecting that place?
なあ、なんかあそこを守っている気がしないか
まあ、奇遇ね、アタシもそう思うわ
What a coincidence. That was my thought, exactly.
But we'll never get through there unless we bomb the place.
しかし、あんなの絨毯爆撃でもしないことには
じゃあ、行ってくるわ
In that case, I'll go.
奏ちゃん
Kanade-chan!
How foolish. That's suicidal!
愚かな
自殺行為だ
いや、まてよ
No, wait.
よっし！
Nice!
Is her combat ability equivalent to that of a bomber?
あれの戦闘能力は爆撃機並か
Let's go.
行きましょう
くそ、もう湧いて来やがった
Damn, more of them are coming already!
Yuri, you go on ahead.
ゆり、先に行け
俺たちはこいつらを片付ける
We'll take care of them.
うん、お願い
All right. Please do.
ああ、任せとけ
That's right, you can count on us.
Second Computer Room
バカにしてる
They're totally making fun of me.
But this time...
けど、今度こそ
Just how many did they steal?
どれだけ盗んだのよ
うん？
There's no doubt about it.
間違いない
I'm amazed you made it this far.
よく辿り着けましたね
バカにしてるの？
Don't screw with me. You even have a plate on the door.
表にこれ見よがしにプレート貼ってあったじゃない
ここは学校ですからね
This place is a school, after all.
おかしな価値観をお持ちのようで
You have a unique sense of humour.
No, no. That's a rule.
いやいや、それがルールなんですよ
A rule set by God?
この世界の、神の
神、存在するか否か
"God."
Highly debatable if He exists or not.
実に深遠なテーマです
興味深い
Very interesting, indeed.
が、それを追求する術は僕にはない
But I don't have the capability to pursue that answer.
ただ決まり事に従うだけ
I only follow the set rules.
アナタもプログラミングで動いてるね？
So you're programmed to do this, too.
お察しのとおりだ
How insightful.
誰がそんなことを？
Who are you working for?
名前を言っても無意味でしょう
What would be the point in giving you the name?
They were here long ago.
遠い昔の人です
「エンジェル·プレーヤー」
Angel Player...
このソフトは何なの？
What exactly is this software?
As you know, it is software that allows one to create and alter materials in this world.
知ってのとおり
この世界のマテリアルを作成、改変出来るソフトです
How is it able to do that?
なんでそんなことが出来るの
さあ
I wonder. I am not the developer.
僕は開発者ではないので
でも、アナタ達も土から武器を製造している
But you all create weapons from dirt.
同じことでしょう
Is that not the same?
So in the end, we're playing by the same rules.
結局、同じルールに則ってるのか
Did the developer of the software want to become God?
そのソフトの製作者は神になりたかったのかしら
さあ
I wonder. I would not know.
僕にはなんとも
Okay, we're short on time, so let's get down to business.
じゃあ、時間が無いから本題に入りましょう
アナタは何が起きたら、こうするように
What was the trigger programmed into you to start all this?
プログラミングされているの
プログラミングの内容は分かりません
I am not aware of the nature of the program.
Then let me rephrase the question.
じゃあ聞き直すわ
あなたにとって、世界に何が起きたの？
What changed about this world, in your perspective?
世界に、愛が芽生えました
Love has developed in this world.
What? "Love"?
えっ？
あい？
Yes, love. That which is not meant to exist in this world.
そう、愛です
それがあってはならない、この世界でな
そうか
He's right. If love develops in this world,
the two involved should disappear instantly.
その通りだ
この世界で愛を覚えたなら
すぐにも消えるはずだ
But if it were to develop and be sustained, what would happen to this world?
でも、それが芽生えたら、この世界はどうなる
愛が芽生えてしまうと
If love develops, this world changes into an eternal Eden.
ここは永遠の楽園に変わります
But this world must not become that.
しかし、この世界はそうなってはいけない
That is because this is a place from which everyone must graduate.
なぜならここは卒業していくべき場所だからです
In other words, that's what someone thought up.
そう思った人がいたのね
However, there are times when people with amnesia wander in here after having a full life,
ただ、誰かの為に生き、報われた人生を送った者が
having lived for people other than themselves.
記憶喪失で迷い込んでくることが稀にある
その時にそういうバグが発生するんです
Glitches like this occur when people like that arrive here.
And the programmer of Angel Player was one such person.
そしてそれが「エンジェル·プレーヤー」のプログラマー
驚きました
What a surprise. You are absolutely correct.
ご明察です
That same programmer found that glitch in this world and made a patch for it.
その人はこの世界のバグに気づき修正をした
それがカゲを使ってのエヌ·ピー·シー化
And that's what's changing people into NPCs by using the shadows.
つまり、リセット
In other words, a reset.
Yes.
はい
So you're telling me some NPCs were once like us?
じゃあ何？
NPCの中にはアタシたちみたいなのが他にも居るってこと？
はい、います
Yes, there is another. Just one.
一人だけ
可哀想に
I pity the person.
そのプログラマーです
It's the programmer himself.
彼は待ち続けました
He continued to wait for the other one who had left this world after learning what love is.
愛を知り、一人この世界を去っていた彼女を
What? There'd be no way for him to meet the other one again.
そんな、もう一度出会える可能性なんてない
天文学的数字ではありますが
The chance is astronomically small, but it isn't zero.
ゼロではありません
しかし、彼女を待つ時間はあまりに長過ぎ
But the time spent waiting was too great, and he couldn't maintain his sanity.
彼はもう正気では居られなかった
That's why he made a program to turn himself into an NPC.
だから、自分をNPC化するプログラムを組んだのです
もしかして、そっちが先だったんじゃないの
Couldn't that possibly have been the original intention for the shadows?
そして同じことが起きないよう
The programmer also applied those to the world itself, so the same thing wouldn't happen again.
世界に敵をさせた
可能性はあります
That is possible.
その人は何時か報われる日がくるのかしら
So will the day ever come when they're rewarded for their actions?
さあ
Who knows?
もう、何が正しいのかなんだか
I don't have a clue what's right.
僕にも何が正しいのかは分かりません
I have no idea what is right, either.
ただ、ここまで辿り着いたアナタならば
But since you have made it this far,
you may be able to discover the answer.
その答えが導き出せるかも知れません
どういう意味よ
What do you mean by that, exactly?
You can change the world based on your will.
アナタの意思次第では
世界を改変出来る、という意味です
What's the point in that?
改変してどうすんのよ
彼が選ばなかった道も選べます
You can choose a path that person did not.
You're saying... I can become God?
それはアタシが神にでもなれる、というの？
言い換えれば
That's a different way of saying it.
I can make this place into an eternal Eden?
ここを永遠の楽園にすることだって出来るの？
That person refused that conclusion, but I would not.
彼はそれを否定しましたが
僕自身は否定しません
いや、否定する感情を持ちません
More accurately, I do not have the capacity for denial.
神？
God? I can become the god of this world?
アタシがこの世界の神？
どうかしましたか？
Is something the matter?
I've made this world mine...
手にいれたんだ、この世界を
I did it!
アタシはやっと
戦ってきたのはこのためだったんだ
This is what I've been fighting for.
I could even beat Tenshi.
天使にだって勝てる
これだけのシステムがあれば
With all of these systems,
最強だ
I'm invincible.
なんて事する訳ないじゃない
As if I'd do that.
奏ちゃんにも、もうそんなことできない
I can't do that to Kanade-chan any more.
Because I... I came this far because I...
だってアタシは
ここまで来たのは
アタシは
あれ
Strange.
愛を感じ取りました
I sense love.
I've never felt it so strongly.
ここまで大きいのは初めてです
It's growing at an incredible rate.
恐ろしい速度で拡大を
なんですか？
What is this about?
だって、アタシがここまでやって来たのは
I came this far because I want to protect everyone.
みんなを守るためなんだから
Ah, so you are the source.
ああ、発生源はアナタでしたか
で、何をしようと言う気です
In that case, what do you intend to do?
すべてのマシンをシャットダウンをしなさい
Shut down every machine here.
Right now.
今すぐ
いいんですか
Are you sure?
Have you considered the consequences?
ちゃんと考えたんですか
まだまだ時間はありますよ
There is plenty of time remaining.
All eternity, in fact.
それこそ永遠に
あのね、教えてあげる
You know what? I'll tell you something valuable.
Humans won't... even wait... for ten minutes!
人間というものは、たったの十分だって
我慢してくれないものなのよ
It's finally... over...
これで、終わった
I'm sure everyone's been saved.
きっと、みんなは助かったはず
They should have been able to leave this place safely.
これで無事この世界から去っていけたはず
にしても、不覚だ
Still, how careless of me.
お姉ちゃんアンタたちと同じぐらい
I cared for everyone here as though they were my siblings.
みんなのこと大切に思っちゃったんだ
アンタたちが誇れるぐらい
I wanted to be like a big sister that cared for you all, so that you could be proud of me.
アンタたちだけを愛する姉でいたかったのに
I've always walked this path alone; when I look back, everyone is so far away.
itsumo hitori de aruiteta furikaeru to minna ha tooku
いつも一人で歩いてた
ああ　この気持は何なんだろう
What is this feeling?
どうしちゃったんだろう
What's become of me?
振り返るとみんなは遠く
●
私をつき動かしていたものが
The force that was driving me forward is fading away.
●
消えていく
If it fades, I won't be able to stay here.
それが消えちゃったら
それでも私は歩いたそれが強さだった
Even so, I kept on walking. That was my strength.
soredemo atashi ha aruita sore ga tsuyosa datta
ここに居られなくなる
．
●
人生はあんなにも理不尽に
The world took away your lives just like that, yet every moment I spent with the people here was a treasure.
．
アンタたちの命を奪い去ったのに
●
なのに、みんなと過ごしていた時間は
かけがえがなくて
"Nothing frightens me any longer", I mumble softly.
mou nanimo kowakunai sou tsubuyaitemiseru
もう何も 怖くない
アタシも
I'm starting to want to follow them...
みんなの跡を
追い掛けたくなってきちゃったよ
そうつぶやいてみせる
ありがとう
Thanks. That's enough now.
もう十分だよ
You don't have to suffer alone, Sis.
もうお姉ちゃんだけ苦しまなくていいよ
長い間お疲れ様、お姉ちゃん
Take a rest from your long fight, Sis.
いつか　人は一人になって
．
Eventually, everyone ends up alone,
itsuka hito ha hitori ni natte
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
．
And is left with only their memories.
omoide no naka ni ikiteku dake
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
In order to appreciate even sorrow and continue smiling,
kodoku sae aishi waratterareru you ni
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
．
I'll keep on fighting,
atashi ha tatakaunda
あたしは戦うんだ
私は戦うんだ
I won't show you my tears.
namida nante misenainda
涙なんて見せないんだ
I've always walked this path alone; everyone has been waiting for me.
itsumo hitori de aruiteta minna ga matteita
いつもひとりで歩いてた　みんなが待っていた
Eventually, everyone ends up alone...
itsuka hito ha hitori ni natte
いつか人は一人になって
...and is left with only their memories
omoide no naka ni ikiteku dake
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
When that times comes, I won't be strong at all,
sono toki ha mou tsuyoku nanka nai yo
その時はもう強くなんかないよ
I'll shed tears with the weakness of a normal girl.
futsuu no onna no ko no yowasa de namida wo kobosu yo
普通の女の子の弱さで涙を零すよ
Next Episode Preview
I'm so glad I was able to spend time with you all.
Thank you so much.
Graduation class speaker, Otonashi Yuzuru!